Chapter 2: Rebuilding

The world spun and gleamed, lightning crackling at the edges of vision while thunder roared at the sound of a whisper. The line between light and darkness blurred, the air distorting as time itself was caught up in the flight of particles, when stone fell upon stone and the very earth was infused with a sense of purpose.

Amidst a whirlwind of magic, a wizard of unparalleled power stood, weaving the threads of raw energy into something solid. Not building, but rather growing the castle from its foundations, Albus Dumbledore raised hallways, towers and empty spaces, the outer structure that would accommodate the greater magics that would support the architecture within. And in every part of the castle, in every room, wall, and even the loose stones, a tiny morsel of magic to contribute to the overall sentience instilled in the castle, that would allow the school to understand and adapt to the needs of the people living within it. Surrounding the castle, the land was sated with concentrated power, nurturing the manifestation of ghosts, and encouraging the growth of magical plants and creatures, and the lure of prophecies. The new Hogwarts grounds would be as grand as the old ones, and provide a safe living place to the many magical races and creatures that used to call Hogwarts their home as well.

Where once the four founders had built together, the old wizard now stood alone. There was much to be done, the work of weeks or even months, but he, more than anyone, understood the Hogwarts that had once been, and at last, after more than a century of life, he had learned the magics to reproduce it. None could help him, for Ignotus Peverell had sworn him to keep the potentially dangerous magics to himself, but it was a small price to pay. It might cost him most of the magic left in his body, but Hogwarts would be restored to its former glory. If he could help it – and he probably could – the new school year would even begin on time. Perhaps the work would not be finished yet, but at least the castle should be inhabitable by September the first.

It had not been an easy decision, but the school would be remade exactly as it had been. Four great Houses, not three as he once would have chosen. For decades, Slytherin House had been a fertile ground for bigotry and intolerance, evidenced in the worst way when its members had flocked en masse to the Dark Lord's call. But before that, Slytherin had a proud history, and produced many outstanding witches and wizards of the light. With Voldemort gone, with the country's power structure changing as it had, there was hope for the House once more. Severus, certainly, would do all he could to bring his House back to its former glory. He deserved to be given the chance.

Nor would there be a fifth House. True, he was doing a founder's work, but it would feel wrong to lend his name to a part of the new Hogwarts. Although – he ruefully admitted to himself – it would be a dear wish if, like Godric Gryffindor, his life would be remembered primarily for his work with Hogwarts rather than for the many wars he had fought. And he could just imagine Minerva's firm voice telling him that he had every right to found a Dumbledore House, and picture her expression when he put her in charge of it...

Oh, Minerva.

Of all the recent war's losses, hers was the one he felt most keenly. The sobering presence of his deputy headmistress had been a constant solace in his life for many decades, and she had been closer to him than anyone still alive. She, of all people, had been supposed to survive him, not die a senseless, pointless death at the hand of some misguided cretin.

It was a bitter irony that, now that the wars of his life were finally over, the conviction that had carried him through all those years was shattered beneath him. For all the friends he had lost, for all the allies he'd sacrificed, there had been the one comfort that, some day, he would be able to apologize to them. In his quiet moments, he had sometimes wondered what it would be like, when the time finally came to lay down his head and go to his rest, to see everyone again on their next great adventure.

Nothing.

There was nothing.

There was no afterlife where his loved ones might be waiting for him. He would never see Aberforth again and be able to beg for his forgiveness. Nor Ariana, nor mother or father. Oh, he could use the resurrection stone, but it would be a paltry thing, and if he took it once, would he ever be able to give it up? Or worse – and even knowing that the first argument should weigh high enough on his mind to stop him, it was this fear above all that turned him away from the temptation – what if they did not forgive him? They had no true life, no capacity for change. If Aberforth had hated his brother when he died, which he had every reason to do, he could never be persuaded to feel differently.

Albus had kept up his outward demeanor, showing nothing of his inner turmoil to the people around him. The world was a fragile place, and he was needed still, perhaps more so now than ever before, to guide the merge of the magical and Muggle civilizations. There were others who might, but in Britain few were experienced and respected enough to do the work that needed doing in these first few years, averting the disasters that might come from sudden, explosive progress, while not blocking the potential good. For all that he might wish to rest, his duty was to wear the mantel of a leader, and that meant that no one could see that something inside him had broken.

He gazed ahead, shaping the magic around him with only half a mind. One thin strand of hope remained. Harry Potter believed, as did Ignotus Peverell, that death could be defeated. That one day, even those who had gone before could be restored to a body. It seemed impossible; a fancy dream, and more than a little dark besides. And yet, that dream was all he had left.

It was not a hope for himself. Even now, death held no fear for him, for he had lived his life, and he knew that soon it would be enough. He had spoken true when the Boy-Who-Lived had asked him this question as a hypothetical. The idea of death, which he had once met with calm and even some joy, felt bitter to him now, but even so, he was still old and weary; he had no wish to linger longer than he must. But if those who had died before their time, at least, could be restored, then that would be a great comfort.

He sighed to himself. Wouldn't it be nice? It was not a hope he could believe in. But perhaps it didn't matter. The Peverell-Potter dream would progress, or it would not, without his help. His task was to make the world the best place it could be for the people who still lived.

And that, he thought with a small smile as he poured his magic into the castle where the clock tower grew before his eyes, was something he could do.

Chapter 4: A Black Trial

Author's Note: In chapter 106 / 26 of Following the Phoenix, we hear a little about Sirius Black, who has granted the Hogwarts delegation access to his parental home in exchange for a trial. There wasn't really an opportunity to resolve this particular plot bunny in the main text, so here's the tale! There will be a bit more background on this in chapter 15.

August 1992.

"The eighty-ninth session of the two-hundred-and-eight Wizengamot is convened at the request of Lord Sirius Black. Lord Black was incarcerated in Azkaban following his arrest in nineteen eighty one and, due to wartime circumstances, not awarded a trial at the time. Today, we will correct this oversight."

Harry looked around at the faces in the Most Ancient Hall. The three Muggle judges who had been assigned to participate in criminal cases in the Wizengamot looked a little ill at ease in their very first session. The magical members showed a variety of expressions, mixed between curiosity, boredom, anger, resentment and excitement. It was unclear who, if any, bought into some of the many conspiracy theories regarding Black. More of them had probably accepted the narrative that he had been Voldemort's right-hand man, which the Daily Prophet had spouted despite the complete lack of any evidence for the claim. Harry hoped that the Muggle judges could manage to instill some sense into the proceedings, but he'd made sure to be there anyway, just in case. It was his first appearance in the Wizengamot since the meeting where he was given power of negotiation. There had been many dirty looks, but nobody had contested that he had the right to be here today, at the trial of the man who had once been named his godfather.

A click of the Chief Warlock's rod silenced the muttering that had risen up. "Let Sirius, Lord of the Noble and Most Ancient House of Black, be brought in."

The doors opened, and a gaunt man was floated in, flanked by six Aurors. His hands and feet were chained, and there was a band around his neck that, Harry knew, was designed to non-lethally incapacitate him if not deactivated every five minutes by a recognized authority. He was pale and skinny, his eyes sunken and his hair matted, even after four months away from Azkaban. Of course, Nurmengard was hardly the best facility to recover from years of Dementor exposure, and the move towards more humane prisons had been slow. For clothes, he wore little but a sleeveless gray robe, the Dark Mark clearly visible on his left arm.

"Sirius Black," Albus Dumbledore boomed when the wizard had been lowered and chained into the metal chair. "You have asked this body to pass judgment for your crimes. To wit: that you knowingly joined a terrorist organization; that you willingly betrayed the location of James, Lily and Harry Potter to your master, in the full understanding that it would most likely lead to their deaths; that you murdered Petter Pettigrew and twelve Muggle bystanders. What do you have to say for yourself?"

Slowly, ever so slowly, the main in chains looked up, taking a deep breath before he spoke.

"Not Sirius," he croaked. He brought his gaze to the Chief Warlock's face, a haunted look in his eyes. "I'm not Sirius. My name is Regulus Black."

Harry silently groaned. Of course the second-most famous Death Eater, who never got a trial, would turn out to secretly be the long-lost twin brother of the real culprit or something like that. Or, Slytherin quickly filled in, Sirius Black never did anything wrong, and was wrongly accused of the crimes of his Death Eater lookalike.

He shot a glance at the Muggle judges, who were showing a mix of confusion, shock and outrage, not just at the prisoner's statement but at the fact that it wasn't immediately dismissed as nonsense. Even the Muggle police, who did not have access to truth serums, mind-reading, memory-viewing and permission to use torture in select cases, would generally be able to confirm an important prisoner's name before sending them to court, let alone imprisoning them. It would take some time to get used to the way things were done in the magical courts.

Harry silently smirked as he sat back and relaxed. This is going to be interesting.

The prisoner sat silently as an Auror performed the identification spells, and in a clipped voice informed the Wizengamot that he was, in fact, Regulus Black. An accomplished wizard might have tricked those spells, but not after ten years in Azkaban, bereft of a wand and kept in a magic-suppressing environment afterwards. Besides, Gringotts could confirm his identity with a simple blood test; the Black family had registered all their children with the bank.

"But he's dead!" Someone on the benches gasped.

The prisoner just turned his head towards the man. He didn't know him, but that didn't mean much, anymore. There were vast gaps in his memory, although it was still surprisingly coherent for the most part; he couldn't remember anymore, of course, but he suspected that there had been preciously little happiness in his life to begin with.

"I am not," he said simply. Then, for good measure, he added: "Would you prefer to ask the goblins, or would it be enough if I told you where to find Sirius's body?"

There was a brief silence, as – hopefully – his message sunk in.

Another, an elderly man spoke up. "Excuse me, but not everyone here is well-versed in the composition of the Noble Houses. Is this a relative of Sirius Black?"

A gray-haired woman stepped forward. Madam Bones, the Director of Magical Law Enforcement. She had spoken to him yesterday to inform him of the details of his trial. "Regulus Black is the younger brother of Sirius Black. He was a known You-Know-Who supporter, but was supposedly executed by the Dark Lord in seventy-nine."

Oh yes, and quite the spectacular public execution that was. His parents and grandfather had been tortured and executed, along with some lowlife polyjuiced to take on Regulus's appearance. But Regulus himself had been kept by the Dark Lord's side, under the Imperius Curse: he was a talented spellcrafter, and therefore too useful to dispose of. Not that that had saved him from his punishment for attempting to flee his master's service, of course.

"But surely the Aurors tested..." Another spoke, trailing of. "Were they so much alike?"

"Yes," the prisoner snarled. "My brother and I never had much in common, but in looks we were rather similar." At least similar enough for a bunch of incompetent Aurors who knew neither of us personally, and couldn't be bothered with the investigative work.

"But if he's not Sirius Black..." A woman spoke slowly, "then he couldn't have betrayed the Potters, could he?"

"Of course not," Regulus bit. "And nor did my brother, for that matter." He glared up at the Chief Warlock. "You never figured it out?"

Old Dumbledore visibly hesitated. "Sirius Black was the Potters' Secret-Keeper. So they all told me, and I personally confirmed it."

"Not the Secret-Keeper. A Secret-Keeper. The other one was Peter Pettigrew. A backup, in case Sirius was killed. He was also, in case you were still wondering, the spy in your precious Order."

It wasn't much of a pleasure to see the Chief Warlock struck dumb, but it would do for now.

The gray-haired woman – Madam Bones – cleared her throat. "I would propose adjourning until after we have completed interrogations –"

Oh Merlin, no. Not another delay.

"– but I can see that this is not in line with the wishes of the Wizengamot. Thus, Lord Black, would you be willing to give us a bit more detail?"

Regulus couldn't suppress a feral grin. He'd been waiting for this moment for over a decade. "Oh yes, Madam Director. With pleasure."

Chapter 7: The Defense Professor

"Hello Professor Riddle."

The specter raised an eyebrow at him. "I don't think I've heard that one before. How much time has passed?"

"It's the 27th of August, still 1992."

"I see. And have you managed to destroy the world yet?"

"Nope. Are you going to ask me that every time I summon you?"

"Quite possibly." The specter shrugged. "How many times have you summoned me now?"

Harry frowned. "This is only the second time." Dumbledore had been adamant that Harry should not lightly talk to the soul of Voldemort. Thinking about it, Harry had reluctantly agreed; spending a good ten minutes considering all the ways he could accomplish malicious goals just by talking had significantly increased his threat assessment of the stone. That was also why there were several hidden cameras around, Hermione was watching from a different room to step in should he find himself getting manipulated, and Dumbledore was on call, just in case. "You don't remember?"

The former Defense Professor looked liked he'd bitten something unpleasant. "Bits and pieces. I remember you calling me before, but those recollections are too hazy to be sure. It is most inconvenient."

It'll certainly make it harder for him to manipulate us, Slytherin suggested.

Assuming he isn't lying, inner Moody pointed out.

Ravenclaw sighed. Need I say it?

Experimenting would require repeatedly summoning someone, probably with some time in between, Hufflepuff said quietly. What about leaving the death at rest?

That's a Dumbledore thing, Slytherin shrugged. We can ignore his silly qualms.

But he is right, Hufflepuff objected. A single occasion to say goodbye and finish off your affairs is one thing, but it seems cruel to repeatedly call someone back in a form that doesn't allow them to interact with the world and even gives them mental impairments. We shouldn't do that unless it's necessary.

Professor McGonagall would probably be happy to help, Gryffindor piped up. But remember that we can't trust Riddle no matter what comes out of those experiments.

"I'm sorry to hear that," Harry said, not sure whether he meant it. "But I have a question about your life before death, which I hope you will answer."

"And why exactly should I help you?"

Harry sighed irritatedly. "We've been over this last time. The more you genuinely help me, the more willing I am to ask you for help, which gives you a greater chance to stop me before I do something stupid that would end up destroying humanity and thereby preventing your eventual resurrection."

Riddle shot him a calculating glare, then shrugged. "Oh, I suppose. What do you want to know?"

"Your curse on the defense professorship. Hogwarts is being rebuilt on a different location. Will that be enough to get rid of the curse?"

"Hmmmm, no, I don't think so."

Harry glared at him. "Then... how can we get rid of it? The current Hogwarts generation may be moderately well-prepared after your teaching, but it would be really nice to not have the same issue again in seven years."

Riddle smirked. "I suppose it would, at that. Tell me, Mr. Potter, if you imagine yourself in my place, how would you have crafted the curse?"

Harry frowned, thinking. "Well, the obvious thing would have been to place some kind of nasty curse on whoever the Hogwarts wards recognize as the Defense Professor – with Salazar Slytherin's knowledge, you can probably do that. But that would be a little too obvious, and Professor Dumbledore said the curse still activated when he renamed the course to Defensive Magic for two years."

"Do not try to reverse-engineer the existing, Mr. Potter," the specter said contemptuously. "I asked how you would do it."

If he were still alive, there's no way I would tell him something like that. Harry thought. It might give him ideas.

Technically, while he was still alive, you did tell him things like that all the time, his inner critic pointed out.

Fine, fine, Harry grumbled. At least he's dead now, and this is something he obviously already thought through.

"I'd consider possible attacks. The obvious thing the Headmaster could do was to rename the course. Or even leave Defense Against the Dark Arts as an existing course, perhaps hire some dying volunteer or a ghost to be sure, and add a new course called calligraphy whose teacher just happens to give interesting instruction."

"Or employ Binns in the position and hire an Auror to teach 'history', yes," Riddle said dryly.

"So if that shouldn't work... No, if you want your curse not to be fooled by the Binns swap you couldn't just curse DADA along with all courses added after the curse was placed. And there's also the possibility to just not swear the Defense Professor into the wards... So if you want to get whoever is really teaching Defense, you'd check the person in the castle who's doing, or being close to, most defensive magic."

"A good idea," Riddle conceded. "However, a curse like that wouldn't catch incompetent professors. the ones who don't do much teaching."

"Wouldn't that accomplish your goals anyway?"

"Arguably, yes, although I'd rather not have an incompetent stuck in the position I was hoping to claim for myself when necessary. However, more problematically, if incompetent teachers were left untouched while the ones doing their job properly were cursed, it would point the Headmaster to exactly this situation, which would make it easier to trace the curse."

"And even if he couldn't, he could just get a dying volunteer to be near regularly scheduled amounts of defensive magic, I suppose."

"Quite. Or he might hire a defense professor who is never actually in class; you can do a lot over a distance, using for instance communication mirrors, especially if classes are supervised by a rotating group of assistants."

"Right. So you want to catch whoever is doing, or supposed to be doing, the Defense Professor's job, no matter what their job title is..." He drew a blank. Magic was intent-based in many ways, true, but for all he'd learned so far, it wasn't that intent-based. You couldn't put human-level understanding in a spell. "Honestly, this is starting to sound like the best way to do it would just be to manually curse whoever is teaching each year. Wait, is that what you did?" That would explain why neither Dumbledore nor any of the curse-breakers he hired has ever been able to find it...

Riddle smiled at that. "You're getting close. But while I'm sure it would have been amusing for a few years, I do have better things to spend my time on. Besides that, I couldn't enter the castle without detection, and it's not so easy to curse someone from a distance."

"So... you got someone else to do it. Someone who's already there." He gasped as the obvious answer clicked into place. "A House Elf. There's hundreds of them in the castle, they stay there for all their lives, and nobody ever pays attention to them."

"And when Hogwarts was destroyed," Tom Riddle said softly. "the dottery old fool saved all the Elves, didn't he?"

"He did," Harry groaned. Not that Harry disagreed with that decision. "So is that the answer then? You put a House Elf under the Imperius?"

"Not the Imperius Curse, no. It interferes with creativity. But House Elves were created to do as they are told, and the Hogwarts Elves are not bound to any individual, but rather to the school. I merely needed to... convince an Elf that creatively making sure that something bad would happen to the Defense Professor every year was in the school's interests. I do believe the Elf ended up quite mad, but Dumbledore would never send him away regardless."

And a House Elf has access to all the teachers' food, to their laundry, to their mail; they can get into your room while you're sleeping without alarm. It wouldn't be at all hard to administer all kinds of interesting potions over a period of months, or otherwise to find secrets you don't want people to know and leak them in the most disastrous way possible. And given that the Elf would have months to plan and prepare, it wouldn't even be that hard to make it seems like an accident each time.

"I guess you got him to back off last year?"

"I made it clear that something bad was going to happen to 'Professor Quirrell' without his help, yes. Anyway, if you get rid of the Elf, the so-called 'curse' will disappear and that should be the end of your Defense Against the Dark Arts problems. Unless the Headmaster practices his usual amount of judgment in the hiring decision, of course – I reject the blame if he sees fit to appoint another half-giant, werewolf or escaped convict to the position."

"He mentioned an Auror, actually. One of the former Azkaban guards. Hermione says he's really nice, although I'm not sure I can believe that."

Riddle shrugged. "So, was that all, then?"

"That was the main thing for now. Although I would still like that list of things you did to avoid the apocalypse."

Riddle smirked. "You want a list? Well then, I hope you brought a large amount of parchment."

Chapter 9: September 1

September 1992.

Michael looked at the faces collected before him. A few were eager, most skeptical. Some were looking downright repulsed. Many of the "purebloods" in the class were not at all pleased to be taught by a Muggle, and were unlikely to be receptive to the material in the first place. They were reluctant high-school students, forced to be here, rather than the mostly willing college students he usually taught.

Why exactly am I doing this again?

He could have just gone back to his work. The freedom of information regarding magic had not brought all that many changes to the average person's daily life yet. He could ignore the whole thing, go back to his research, and teach people who actually wanted to be taught. He could be rid of magic, mostly, live like a normal person. But he couldn't go back to his old life, because one very important part of it was missing.

There was still hope. Petunia's body was perfectly preserved, and Harry was convinced that he could bring his mother back. But as it was, that just put Michael in a strange limbo state where he could neither move on, nor back to what he had had. He didn't want to take up his usual routine, only to come home to an empty house every night. For the sake of his sanity, he needed a change.

That was why he had requested a one-year sabattical, and accepted Professor Dumbledore's job offer. This year, all classes would follow the same curriculum, which would save him preparation time and leave him with plenty of leisure to study magic. Just because he was taking a one-year break didn't mean he was going to put his career on hold, after all. Little fondness thought he felt for magic, it was clear that funding opportunities in the near future would be significantly better for those who understand its basics. Why should he not be one of the pioneers of magical bio-chemistry?

The clock ticked over to 10:15. Michael cleared his throat.

"Welcome, all, to your first class of Science and Rationality."

Li beamed at the class before him. He knew he had some enormous boots to fill, but at least he wasn't secretly the shade of Lord Voldemort, which surely counted in his favor.

"Good morning, class! I am Professor Xiaoguang Li, your new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher. You may address me by my first name, but I will take points for pronouncing it incorrectly."

He was going to enjoy this.

Lisa Fournier looked at the class of English students. She hadn't expected to land a job as a teacher – her subject of mastery was well-covered in France, and, despite the lack of people with any grasp of the subject across the channel, the position had not been expected to come available for some centuries. Well, she wasn't one to look a gift horse in the mouth.

"Welcome to your first class of History! Yes, that is history, not history of magic. This semester we will cover the origins of earth, early civilizations such as ancient Mesopotamia, Egypt, China, Ireland and Greece, and we will end with known history and common speculations about Atlantis. Next semester we will move on the Roman Empire, celtic and germanic culture, towards the early Middle Ages..."

Chapter 10: A Free Elf

Dobby was a free Elf.

For as long as he could remember, he had wondered about freedom – guiltily. He didn't even know, exactly, when he'd admitted the wish to himself. But over the years it had only grown, almost to the point of pain.

Dobby knew he was crazy. Elves did not wish for freedom. Elves existed to serve. An Elf without work, without a master, was... nothing.

And Dobby did love working. He had no desire to do anything else; what did leisure time even mean? It was the Elf Bond that galled him. His master had complete authority over everything in his life. If his master wanted to let off steam by using the Cruciatus Curse on him, he had to take it without complaint. If his master told him to see to his own punishment for minor transgressions, he had no choice but to comply, to the point where he was constantly nursing injuries and could only barely stop himself from ramming his head into the wall for having rebellious thoughts. If his master wanted him to poison the unattended cup of the wife of a political opponent, he had to do it, no matter what he himself might feel for the people involved.

Then, after years and years of silent longing, Dobby's chance had finally come. The Great and Noble Harry Potter had talked to the non-magical humans, and among many other things, they had made the wizards agree to free any Elf who asked for it. Freedom was within his reach; all he'd have to do was to pop to the new Department of Magical Races in the Ministry of Magic, and they'd summon his Master and force him to give Dobby clothes there and then.

And yet he'd stalled. With his old Master he wouldn't have hesitated a second, but the young Master was not like his father. He didn't kill people, or play nasty political games – at least not yet. He didn't even visit needless cruelties on the Elf, and had gone so far as to tell him to "stop constantly beating yourself up for no good reason, it's distracting". He was still likely to snarl at the Elf when he noticed him, or otherwise act dismissively, but if the old Lord Malfoy had been more like his son, Dobby would probably never have come to desire freedom so much.

But the wish had grown, and it hadn't left with Lucius Malfoy's death. It was just that, with the immediate prospect of actually getting his wish, the thought terrified him too. He dreaded the idea of not having a master; what would he do with himself?

That was until he'd heard of the Open Call for Creatures.

The advertisement had been placed in the human newspapers, but it was spoken in whispers among the Elves. Members of all non-human magical races are invited to apply to the British Space Agency for research purposes. What they wanted the volunteers to do was potentially dangerous work, and the more controllable magic the applicant had, the better. An Elf would be perfect; but most of the Elves were far more interested in serving their masters, and if an Elf was ordered by their master to go, the BSA would be bound to reject such a non-volunteer.

He had gone to the address listed in the papers and volunteered. Then he had found his Master and asked for clothes. The young boy had looked shocked, but – surprisingly – perhaps a little relieved as well. Had Dobby reminded him of his father too much? Whatever the reason, he had not protested, but simply passed Dobby a sock.

And now, here he was, among human astronauts, on his first lunar mission. He was to test whether House Elf magic still worked, and whether being away from earth's magical field would hurt him or otherwise have strange effects. It was entirely possible that he would die, but so far (he thought, as he stared at the stars outside the rocket) everything seemed to go well. And if he could survive there without ill effects, the humans would finally have enough security to take the risk of sending a phoenix. From there, the possibilities were endless.

Dobby was a free Elf. He would no longer serve a single human. He would serve all of humanity.

Chapter 11: Moon Phoenix

"Okay, Xare. You see the place, right? Go there, stay just for a bit, and then come back. But if you're in trouble, get back here immediately, okay?"

"Caw." It sounded a little disgruntled – the phoenix did not like going places without her master – but she would do it.

"Then go. And come back in one piece!"

With a burst of flame, Xare disappeared.

Hermione waited, her heart beating rapidly. Less than two seconds later, the fire-bird appeared on the big screen ahead, wings flapping.

This was the final test. If Xare was alright on the moon, Hermione herself would finally be allowed to go. She had done all kinds of experiments, and she'd been put through a version of basic astronaut training. Her space suit was specifically fitted for her and its life-support system was tested to withstand magic. There was, right now, a rocket on the moon, with a spare place to take her back should anything go wrong. Professor Sinistra had gone on the previous mission, and verified that witches could withstand space like normal astronauts. Hermione had used Ignotus's spell, and verified that astronauts did not lose their soul. Testing with the resurrection stone had indicated that even for those who had died in space, the soul was unharmed. Everything suggested it was perfectly safe for her to go.

"Xare is being here," sounded a squeaky voice over the computer. Dobby, the little House Elf who had volunteered to go along on this mission as, basically, a guinea pig. He was a creature of magic who could reason and speak; if anything was causing problems for magical creatures, he would notice. But he hadn't experienced any problems; even his magic worked perfectly. Better than human magic for that matter. He hadn't tried anything potentially risky yet, like Apparition, but he would start experimenting with that the moment she was there and able to quickly bring him to a hospital should things go wrong. (And hadn't it been hard to get the excited Elf to agree not to take unnecessary risks. He clearly didn't value his life very much.)

There was a burst of flame, and Xare appeared before her, looking quite happy. On the screen, she flapped her wings a last time, then burst into flame and left. Xare had come faster than the signal; this strongly suggested that phoenixes were not constrained by the speed of light. They'd analyze the exact time of disappearance and appearance using a computer, of course, but it matched the tentative hypothesis from the testing data they'd already acquired on earth.

"Caw?"

"Yes, Xare," she beamed, looking at the commander, who nodded at her. "Let's go."

Chapter 13: And the Bad

Annika glared at the outlandishly dressed man as he casually strolled to the wine shelves and pocketed five bottles of high-quality vintage. The man utterly ignored her as he added a number of fine cheeses to his bag, summoned several bars of chocolate from a distant aisle with a flick of his wand, and finally disappeared with a sharp crack.

Ever since the secrecy of the magical world had been lifted, life had taken a decided turn for the worse. Oh, it had looked promising at first, when that kid from England had given his big speech. The people in Sweden were not so fortunate, though. It had only taken two days before their own wizards appeared on TV, making it clear that magical Fennoscandia was not governed like magical Britain was, and that its citizens had no intention of bowing to the Muggles. They had spoken the word with a sneer, as though it were a deep insult. Instead, the normal, Muggle, politicians had quickly negotiated a pact of non-interference with the wizards. Normal people and their government would not interfere with the magical side of the country in any way, and in exchange, wizards would leave them alone.

But they hadn't.

Once everything had calmed down, wizards (and witches, she supposed) were seen in the open more and more. But they didn't act like they were guests in the normal people's cities; they behaved as though they were the nobles and everyone else were serfs. The first time this wizard had come to take items from the shop, he had surprised everyone by just disappearing without paying. The second time, the shop owner had approached him, but the wizard had done something with his wand that had the man screaming in pain, and left him with hallucinations for days. They hadn't bothered him since, but they all felt the loss in their paychecks as the shop had to recoup its losses somehow or go bankrupt.

Nor was this wizard the only one. There were talks of thefts, of people getting covered in boils for "showing disrespect", or disappearing altogether... Lately, there'd been quite a few tales of young women who had found themselves at work or school in the morning with no memory of the previous night. None of those stories appeared in the national newspapers or on television, but they were printed in local magazines. Or, more commonly, repeated in hushed whispers.

The police didn't do anything. They might investigate complaints, but they had been given strict instructions to simply forward their conclusions and leave the magical "Aurors" to police their own kind. When Annika had pressed them for action, the senior officer had explained that they genuinely had no options: they had neither weapons nor knowledge to deal with wizards, and the national police absolutely refused to support interference with magic. The politicians didn't even acknowledge that there was a problem.

Then, in the last month, international channels had been removed from the standard TV package, supposedly due to lack of interest, although everyone she knew had only started watching the BBC more since the magic war. Meanwhile, the national news was showing fewer and fewer updates about foreign magical advances. The country's borders were still open, but she suspected that this was only a matter of time.

Annika wasn't stupid; she could see what was happening. There was no way that not a single party would have objected to the current arrangement; at the very least some populist idiot should have cast a throwaway-vote just to be contrary. But that little girl from Britain had talked about memory-altering spells; couldn't those be used to make a group of politicians think that they had agreed? Could there be even easier spells to put the leaders and the press of a country under magical control? It seemed more than likely.

And the people were letting it happen. Even as their democracy was eaten away, as the offenses grew worse and their own options to fight it were steadily eroded, there was no uprising. The wizards were chipping away at the fundamental rights and freedoms of the common people until there was nothing left; and by the time the non-magical people realized that they should revolt, it would be too late to succeed.

Hopefully, the UN would intercede. Surely foreign wizards would understand what was happening? Or was the same thing happening everywhere?

If there was no help from outside to be had, there was still one point of hope, one group who might help. The Fennoscandian wizards, in their television appearance, had made it clear that they were a proud nation with a long history; and that, contrary to some nations, no new blood was admitted into their midst. But that girl from Britain had been new blood – Muggleborn, she'd called it. If all those Muggleborns from Fennoscandia were not inducted into the magical world... were they still out there somewhere?

Chapter 14: Spellcrafting

November 1992.

"So." the professor sat down next to where the two of them were studying in his chambers. "Does magic make more sense when you add in mathematics?"

"Yes," his son said empathetically. "Absolutely. It's actually kind of obvious, really."

Hermione nodded happily in agreement. "Isn't it amazing what you learn when you read books and study what wise old wizards have already discovered?"

Harry shot her a glare, and she poked her tongue out. She'd earned the right to be a little smug on this one.

"I'm hardly going to deny the usefulness of a Wise Old Wizard now that I'm apprenticed to Ignotus," he pointed out. "But in all fairness, we wouldn't have learned any of this until fifth year without him." He turned back to his father. "For some reason, the department of education in the Magical Ministry doesn't think that twelve-year-olds can learn mathematics yet, and the Arithmancy elective doesn't even explain the theory of spellcrafting until after teaching all the relevant mathematical techniques."

"I think there's a reason for that, actually," Hermione said. "If they moved too fast, someone might start experimenting and get themselves killed."

"True," Harry said more soberly, and a little self-consciously. "I suppose someone might. Don't worry, Dad. I'm doing theory only."

For now, Hermione thought, but she wisely held her tongue. The professor was looking alarmed enough as it was.

"The basic idea is very simple," Harry quickly continued. "See, obviously the universe doesn't have a special case for someone saying Wingardium Leviosah."

His father nodded. "Obviously."

"Right. And the reason it requires such a strange spell is that floating an item the way that spell does isn't basic. There is a core effect of magic to lift an item using your own magic, canceling its gravity. There is a core effect to make an item go up. There is another effect to give an object a sort of nudge, changing tis direction, and one to regulate its speed. The spell doesn't just float an object, it applies the lifting effect, gives the object an initial push upwards, and then passes mental control over the speed and direction effects to the caster. It's a computer program."

"Without the computer I suppose," Harry's father said absently. "All that in such a short spell – that must be a very efficient language."

"It has to be," Hermione spoke up. "Longer spells, with more actions, put a large strain on the caster's wand – if the spell is too long, it'll just fail. But there are quite a few ways to combine effects and lift them towards actual spells. The art of spellcrafting is to find a way to efficiently combine basic effects into either a spell that's short enough to cast, or at least something that can be split up into multiple spells. N.E.W.T. students usually don't get beyond a level where they can combine more than a few simple effects before pushing the limits of most wands, though."

"Limits which, incidentally, are a lot more lenient with the elder wand," Harry added.

"I see," the professor said. "That sounds intriguing. And how exactly can this get you killed?"

"Side effects," Hermione explained, as Harry groaned softly. "When you string a lot of magical effects together into a short spell, there's a chance that you trigger some effects that you hadn't been aiming for as well, more so if the spell is more compressed. In some cases it's even unavoidable that you get side effects – in which case the goal is to avoid the more detrimental ones. The problem is that there is no way to directly list what side effects might occur – you can figure it out on an individual basis, but it's very easy to miss some possibilities. And that's where it gets dangerous."

"Hmmm. But I guess if they allow students to do it, you won't get a side effect that blows up the school when trying to do something simple."

"Right. There are a lot of basic magical effects – tens of thousands, at least – but they're in connected groups. So if you try to make a charm to conjure floating lights, you might end up causing stench or maybe setting things on fire, but you won't accidentally blow yourself up. You can blow yourself up when designing attack spells, but unless you involve specific power multiplier techniques, side effects still cannot cause you to blow up the school. And there is no realistic way to use these basic effects to do what Merlin would call 'true devastation', although that's a pretty high bar. It is still possible to destroy an area of a few miles across or permanently mutilate someone's soul or something like that. Those effects aren't taught before Master level, though."

The professor twitched briefly, and turned to Harry. "Except you are studying spells to manipulate the soul."

"Well yes," Harry conceded. "And there are quite a few effects in that group which can hurt the soul if misapplied, so any screwup could be disastrous. But I'm not casting any of this. I'm just doing the maths, and right now, all the grub work of learning the possible effects, how they must be applied, and how they work together. I won't even think of casting anything before Ignotus approves it, and he's supposed to be an expert on this. I promise I'm not about to risk my magical mind-backup immortality device, Dad."

"I guess that's the best I can hope for." Professor Verres looked somewhat grim. "Although I do still worry. You know I'll never forgive myself for not stopping you if you do get hurt."

"Dad... It's not like you could actually stop me. This is something I just have to do."

"I know," he sighed. And with your mother's life at stake... Well, I guess I'm selfish. But at least stay as careful as you can be." He shook himself, then glanced at Hermione with a hint of embarrassment. "Anyway. As I understood it, you managed to create a spell last year. But you didn't know any of this then, did you?"

"Sort of," Harry nodded. "But that's a bit of a different case. You see, the basic magical effects are necessarily limited in what you can do with them. But it's also possible to create new effects, which do not necessarily have any limitations. It's not easy, though. To create a new effect requires a strong emotion or mental state, usually – but not always – a lot of magical power, and some unknown factor as to whether the universe allows it. You also typically have to create the effect as a part of a larger spell to be able to do anything with it. For example, the Patronus Charm uses seventeen different basic effects, while the core of the spell is powered by the emotion of ignoring death. I simply changed the powering emotion while keeping the rest of the spell unaltered. It really was more of a change than a new creation, but I guess it did create a new magical effect, so it counts for the Interdict of Merlin. The Interdict makes sure people can only access emotion-fueled effects if they have learned them from a living mind."

"Inconvenient. Although necessary, I suppose. But how can there be so many 'powerful spells', then? I would imagine the emotional spectrum to not be that large."

"It's a powerful emotion channeled towards a specific purpose," Harry explained. "The Killing Curse for instance doesn't require just hatred – which could easily fuel many spells – but the explicit and absolute wish for someone to die. In the Patronus case, I used my abhorrence of death for the specific purpose of destroying a Dementor. The spell ended up doing a lot more, partially due to those other seventeen effects and partially because of what I was thinking and feeling at the time, but as you can imagine there are easily millions of emotion-driven goals."

"True," the professor nodded thoughtfully. "But I suppose this is all irrelevant to you – you only need to work with basic effects for now, right?"

"No, actually," Harry answered. "Ignotus taught me several soul-related emotion-fueled spells he and his brothers developed during their life – Cadmus, mostly; he was very emotional. He thinks I might be able to use one or more of the effects if I can isolate it from the rest of the spell. I haven't really gotten to the point of analyzing that, though."

"Do you need help? I'm sure we could easily get a mathematician to work with you. Or if it's all exact work, perhaps even a computer programmer?"

"There are already some Muggles studying arithmancy," Hermione observed. "A group in Spain got the security clearance last month – mixed mathematicians and computer scientists. And they are planning to let a computer take over at least some of the work." She'd been very enthusiastic when hearing about that project, even if a small and rather silly part of her was sad that she couldn't join the group herself. But then, she didn't have the expertise, and even Time-Turners and phoenixes had their limits. "I don't think it would be easy to make a computer understand the consequences of combining certain magical effects, but it probably could propose a design and tell you what side effects you risk. It would be an invaluable tool in spell design. But they have to attain a mastery in arithmancy before they can really get anywhere, so it'll probably be a few years at least."

"Which is longer than I can wait," Harry added. "I want to finish this before the Suspension Charms on Mum and McGonagall and the Hogwarts students wear out. And there's a lot of red tape to go through to involve Muggles in this sort of thing as well. Dumbledore and the rest of his lot are adamant that we cannot have competition-driven publication pressure, because that might lead to information being released that could be dangerous, yada yada, so it probably isn't worth the trouble. Besides, the main work for now isn't the mathematics, it's figuring out what to do and to avoid in the first place. And since there aren't any soul-arithmancy experts alive except for Ignotus, it would probably be a bad idea to start on any actual spells before he okays the plans I have."

"Do you really think you'll get this done before the Suspension Charms wear out?" Hermione asked quietly. "Without resorting to spells that might be dangerous?"

"The Suspension should last for almost two years. And don't forget that, with the elder wand – and Dumbledore's own power – I have a lot more leeway in the spell design than an arithmancer would normally have. That should make it possible to avoid most of the nastier side effects or the truly unexpected behavior. And with the philosopher's stone, and Ignotus's help... I really think it's not unrealistic that we might start resurrecting people in the summer."

"And you're sure he will help?" Professor Verres-Evans asked.

Harry just sighed, and shared a look with Hermione. "I think so. And I really hope so."

Chapter 15: Lord Black

December 1992.

Lesath carefully opened the door to the hospital room and slipped inside. There wasn't much need to act inconspicuous, really – he'd been called here, after all. But the habits of a lifetime were hard to break, and he was nervous today, as he had no idea what this man wanted from him.

Regulus Black, sitting upright on the bed, looked him over coolly. "Lesath Lestrange?"

Lesath approached the bed and gave a short bow, as Professor Snape had instructed him. "Lord Black," he spoke neutrally.

"You may call me uncle. You're Bella's brat, aren't you?"

Lesath stiffened involuntarily. The man waved it off.

"I don't mean offense – that's just how I remember you. You were a baby last time I saw you. In fact, I remember you screaming a lot. Gave me headaches you did."

"I'm... sorry?"

Lord Black shrugged. "You were probably perfectly well-behaved most of the time – but I wouldn't remember, would I?" His voice turned quiet. "Your parents were there too, weren't they? Do they even know they had a kid?"

Lesath swallowed. "No."

His new uncle just nodded. "Cherish that. It means that even your irritating moments were good memories to them. At least you know your parents once loved you, which is far more than my brother and I ever had."

But they don't now. Lesath forced away the lump in his throat. He shouldn't allow this man to make him vulnerable.

"Why did you ask me to come here?"

Lord Black nodded approvingly. "To the point, I see. Well then... do you know why I asked to be given a trial?"

"To... get free, Lord B- uncle?"

The man snorted. "Hardly. I was caught as a Death Eater, which carries a life sentence. I had no realistic hope of being released. I still don't know how it happened, although I guess it has something to do with the court suddenly being overrun by Muggles."

Lesath stayed quiet at the obvious distaste in the man's voice. Lord Potter – Harry – had warned him about this. Lord Regulus Black was not truly evil; he had served the Dark Lord at his parents' behest, but had recoiled from the bloodshed and futilely tried to escape. However, he was a true blood purist; Muggles, in his view, were little more than dogs. There was no reason to hate them, but you wouldn't let dogs, or people raised by dogs, have any say in how normal people lived their lives. The large Muggle-murder he was famous for had largely been an accident: he cared so little about Muggles that he simply hadn't noticed that they were in the line of fire when he sent his most powerful blasting curse at his brother's murderer.

"No," Lord Black continued. "My sole purpose was to preserve the Black bloodline and restore the family honor. If I died without an heir, our line would end – and to add insult to injury, we'd be disgraced as followers of a madman. But if I was officially convicted, I could at least clear my brother's name and exercise the Lord's right to appoint an heir."

Lesath's heart suddenly started hammering wildly in his chest. Could the man be insinuating what he seemed to be insinuating? "But you were freed."

"True." His uncle shook his head sadly. "But my time is past. The Dementors took a lot from me; I lasted because I had a purpose, but I doubt I'll live long anymore, and I have no patience for a wife. Plus, I don't think I could adjust to the new politics anymore – something I hear you are quite adept at. You've done well for yourself, haven't you?"

That was the first time someone had ever said that to him. But surprisingly, there was even some truth in it – recently. Ever since his role on Dark Monday, people had looked at him differently. He'd spent the summer working for the DMLE – and occasionally for Muggle organizations – as a sort of messenger boy. He'd negotiated visiting rights with his parents. Children of "light" families were suddenly willing to talk to him, and there had been far less bullying this year. He'd even struck a tentative friendship with some of the other children who'd been in the makeshift Hogwarts orphanage, and those friendships had lasted in the school as well.

"I guess..."

Lord Black gave him a long look.

"You remind me a little of me, when I was your age." He smiled, briefly. "I'm offering to take you as my heir, Lesath, but you can refuse. I do have other options. But I hope you'll accept, because you're the best. I've looked through your files."

"I'm just a bastard..."

"All the better – it means that the Black family has first claim on you. You're my closest family – you and your cousin Nymphadora, but she's a half-blood, quite attached to her family name, and I doubt she'd even be interested – she already has her life planned out. I think you will do well."

"I... What exactly does it mean?" He stalled.

"I'll give you the lessons in etiquette and politics my parents gave me. I'll expect you to behave in a manner befitting the Heir of a Noble and Most Ancient House. You'll make connections, learn to manage money, and when you're ready, you'll take up the Lordship." He paused briefly, staring away from Lesath.

"I will not repeat my parents' mistakes," he added softly. "I won't try to force my beliefs on you. I won't even choose a wife for you, provided you at least marry a witch – unless you ask me to, of course. The most important thing is to preserve the family, and show a proud, strong face to the world. If that means adapting to current politics and ideas, so be it – Merlin knows I wouldn't be able to do it, but you're young and unmarred."

"I'm not sure I even have political ideas."

"I'm not that much better. As you might know, I haven't had much chance to apply myself. But you're young, you have time. Form beliefs. Make connections. As the future Lord Black, you'll be invited to many parties as a matter of courtesy, and there's always discussion there. I'll teach you how to conduct yourself in the beginning, and in time, you'll learn from experience how to participate on a deeper level."

Honestly, that sounded terrifying. Okay, a part of him would really love to see the faces of Carl Sloper and his cronies when they found out their former target was the future Lord of a Noble and Most Ancient House, but he couldn't do this, surely he couldn't do this. There was no way someone like him could take that kind of responsibility. Besides, he was sworn to a live of servitude – perhaps not formally, but he'd given his word, and that meant just as much.

But then... he had a pretty good idea what Lord Potter would say. With this role, you can do a lot of good. As Lord Black, he could formally ally their Houses, bring a key family vote to the Wizengamot... As Lord Black... his thoughts stumbled at the idea. That couldn't be him, not without someone telling him how to do everything.

"Aside from your responsibilities, of course," Lord Black continued, "you will be given all possible support, the formal backing of the House in conflicts, tutors if you need them; you'll be allowed to live in the Grimmauld house, have status roughly similar to that of the Malfoy heir, and of course when you're ready to take up the Lordship, you'll inherit the Black fortune. I believe it's currently about a hundred and seventy thousand Galleons."

Lesath fainted.

Author's Note: chapter 4 (A Black Trial) has been expanded a bit – just look after the horizontal line!